TROY GOODEN

Software Engineer

- +1-917-208-5052
- ▼ Tro12185@gmail.com
- ♠ NY / D.C. / ATL
- Linkedin.com/in/
 troygooden/
- TroyGood.dev
- Medium.com/
 @tro12185

Skills -

Front End



- Javascript (ES5/ES6)
- React 16.8
- Redux 4.04
- HTML5
- AJAX
- Bootstrap 4
- CSS

Back End



- Node, NPM
- Ruby on Rails
- PostgreSQL
- MySQL

Miscellaneous



- Git
- Test Driven Development
- Computer Hardware
- Telecommunications

Summary^{*}

Software engineer specializing in Front-End web technologies. Provide indepth knowledge about maintaining and constructing network hardware infrastructure while also providing solid knowledge to facilitate a software engineering role. Experienced in the telecommunications industry, customer service and sales. Offer strong leadership, teamwork and problem solving skills & commended for consistently going above and beyond expectations.

Technical Projects

React Resort (hotel clone) - Link to GitHub | Link to Demo

- Developed a dynamic, small boutique hotel website
- · User can dynamically filter room options
- Technology: React, Context API, FontAwesome

RPS Hero - Link to GitHub | Link to Demo

- Developed a turn-based sprite game
- Level up by defeating enemies and go straight to the leaderboards
- Technology: Javascript, HTML, Ruby on Rails, NES.css, Bootstrap
 Affirm Action Link to GitHub & Demo
- Developed a Quote/Poetry/Video notification web app
- · User receives notifications of affirmations based on subscription
- Technology: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React, Redux, React Cards, Twilio API, Reddit API

Education –

Flatiron School - July 2019

 Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, Unit Testing, JavaScript and React immersive program
 York College - June 2007

Professional Experience

Verizon

Staten Island, NY



May 2018 - April 2019

Fiber Optic & Plant Engineer

- Conducted optical network testing, router installation, networking
- Continually integrated and redesigned network Plant enabling internet service for customers
- · Created or updated technical documentation for network installations
- Effectively worked in teams to implement work orders

BBH Solutions

Jericho, NY



Sep 2017 - May 2018

Voice & Data Technician

- · Successfully installed fiber optic networks for private associations
- Built IT closets with backboards, cross connects, racks, patch panels, and fiber optics
- · Tested, adjusted and solved problems with connections
- Setup and scaled servers on Google cloud farm

Spectrum / Charter Cable

Queens, NY



May 2007 - May 2018

Technical Operations

- Efficiently calibrated, monitored, programmed and troubleshot devices
- Completed logs and work orders to beat company time frame deadlines, maintaining a 5% repeat/error rate
- Led & trained 40+ new hires for small team projects
- Delivered prompt, accurate and excellent customer service